Previously onGotham...
The infected are being killed
all over the city.
I'm the one you seek.
I am Ra's al Ghul.
This man is your past.
Now, embrace your future.
Use the waters, Bruce.
You were the one time
I let love weaken me.
I want you around
as a constant reminder
to never make that mistake again.
No!
I heard about Alfred.
Is he gonna be okay?
You don't give a damn about Alfred
and you sure as hell
don't care about me.
- I know you better than that.
- I thought you did.
Jonathan Crane's father
made a toxin
from the adrenal glands
of his victim.
All they experience is terror.
- What do you want?
- I'm tired of just surviving.
I want more.
I'm sorry, Alfred.
I've been trying to find
who I am for so long.
Who am I supposed to be?
Money, now!
You need to find your true north
and let that guide you.
You've always picked up the Penguin.
I know.
Money, now!
- Please, don't hurt us.
- Give it to me.
Hurry up, all of it.
Give me the ring.
I'm trying.
You have one chance.
Walk away.
Who's this?
I...
I got a license.
Never gonna give you up
Never gonna let you down
Never gonna run around
and desert you
Never gonna make you cry,
Never gonna say goodbye
Never gonna tell a lie and hurt you
Nobody move.
Jewelry, watches, wallets.
You know the drill. Let's go.
- We wanted all.
- All your money.
- Hey, you.
- Come on. Oh, nice. Thank you.
- Oh, jackpot.
- Hey you.
Let me see that.
Cheapskate, huh.
- Come on.
- Hey, careful.
Excuse me.
Hi.
- That's Victor Zsasz.
- I know who it is.
What do you want?
Oh, I was just passing by
heard the ruckus.
You know you can't commit a crime
in Gotham now
without a license
from Penguin, right?
Is it right?
Well, we just started it
so words still getting out.
We're kicking half our take
to that little creep.
Well...
...that's a problem.
Maybe you ain't notice,
but there's four of us
and only one of you.
My finger!
No license, no crime.
Now, drop the loot and blow.
You tell Penguin he hasn't heard
the last of this.
And stay out.
I can't thank you enough.
Don't bother
because you see those guys
they do have a license.
Mazel tov.
Seriously?
No.
Best wedding ever.
You know, we appreciate
all you've done.
Do you?
Three months ago,
following the Tetch incident,
this city was in flames.
I came to you
and offered to, cut crime in half
and I delivered.
Violent crime is down 57%.
But now, you want to literally
unionize crime.
- I mean, but we can't possibly...
- Quiet!
I remember when I sat there.
In the mayor's chair.
I do not envy you.
Or you.
Commissioner of police
and a city notorious for crime.
That's why I wanna help.
Yeah, but we are fully aware
of all you've done.
Are you?
What do you think really happened
to those hordes of criminals
who once prowled our streets?
I'll tell you. I hunted them down...
- No, no, no.
- I made Gotham safe.
Me.
But this is Gotham City.
There will always be crime.
What I am offering is crime
in the hands of professionals.
And held to agreed upon terms...
from which you'll profit.
God bless, America.
You have a choice.
An era of calm and prosperity.
Or return to the good old days.
And they will return
with a vengeance.
We deny everything to the press.
What you need to worry about
is the G.C.P.D.
When one of your officers
finds someone committing a crime,
if that person has a license,
they walk away.
3% each from the day.
Two, to split between you.
- Two and a half.
- One.
- You...
- Yes, fine. Done.
Excellent.
Well, if you'll excuse me
I have to go prepare
for the grand opening
of my new club, The Iceberg Lounge.
Good luck.
Smile, gentlemen. It's a new day.
- Hi, Frank.
- Morning, Jim.
I'll get you coffee in a second.
Sure.
- Morning.
- Good morning.
- Everything okay, Frank?
- Everything's fine, copper.
I got a license.
Penguin approved.
- Is that right?
- Yeah.
I'll take that coffee to go.
What the hell are you doing?
- Look, I got a license.
- Yeah.
And unless you shut up...
...you're also gonna get a fat lip.
We got a problem?
Penguin guarantees these numbers?
Mr. Cobblepot has negotiated them
with the Mayor and Commissioner.
It's a damn good numbers.
But I already heard
from the Commissioner
we have to play ball.
What the hell are you doing here?
Compliance
with the licenses is key.
Mr. Cobblepot worries
about Detective Gordon.
He has a history.
My men will honor the licenses.
You let me worry about Gordon.
Now, get the hell out of my office.
- Who was that?
- A dung beetle.
What's up?
I pulled this...
...off of some guy
robbing my corner bar.
You're a homicide detective.
Isn't stick up a little, JV?
I'm a cop. I see a crime, I stop it.
This is the second one of these
I've come across
- and I'm not the only one.
- Yeah.
Harvey.
Harvey, we cannot let this slide.
Words come down
from the Commissioner.
You find someone
with one of those, they walk.
And before you get on your
high horse three months ago
this city was in a tailspin.
We survived because Penguin
took control of the underworld.
I am not giving this city
over to Penguin.
I don't care
what the commissioner says.
What about your fellow cops
on the past month?
- How many have been shot?
- None. I know the stats.
Jim, we will bust Penguin one day.
I promise you.
But this city has to get back
on her feet.
- Please.
- Harvey, I get that.
But everyday the citizens
of Gotham look to Penguin
and not the G.C.P.D.
to keep them safe
the harder it's gonna be
to win them back.
You want people to trust cops?
There are better ways in doing it
than spitting in Penguin's eyes.
You see one of these, you walk.
Bloody Penguin.
There must be some way
we can turn this against him.
Oh, just... just stop.
Stop right there.
How does this fit in
to what we're doing?
What was the initial reason
that you popped on that mask
and you went out there?
We agreed that I have to be ready
for when Ra's al Ghul returns.
You, yourself, said
there's no substitute
for real world encounters.
But my point is if that is
our mission, we must hold to it.
My finger was on the button
that released the virus.
- Oh, I see.
- I know I didn't press it,
but I feel responsible
for what happened.
And more than that, I could make
a difference in Gotham, Alfred.
- I know I can.
- And that is what we call
mission creep, Master Bruce.
You are trying to achieve
not one but two objectives.
So, go on then.
Which one is your priority?
It's messy, sir.
It's dangerous.
I hear you, Alfred.
But I can prepare myself for Ra's
and make Gotham safer.
You have to trust me.
All inmates to the platform
in five minutes.
Make your way to the door.
Secure the...
This way.
Hey, Warden Reed.
Warden Reed is the boss here.
- Where is he?
- This way.
Back when I was in orderly in here
he'd always talk about his dad
and this formula he'd made.
Some sort of scare juice.
Make you see your greatest fear.
Well, we get a hold of that.
We don't gotta worry about Zsasz
or Penguin.
Or nobody.
What's wrong with him, anyway?
The toxin his father
injected him with
have reloaded Jonathan's
fear response.
His mind created a sort
of bogeyman figure.
Now, it haunts him.
I find it very useful for...
...controlling him.
Jonathan,
you're going with these men.
What? Wait, where are you taking me?
We just want to give someone
a little scare.
Excellent.
Yeah, that's all...
That's all my dad's stuff.
Look, I can't be here after dark.
Please, I really,
I cannot be here after...
You were your daddy's
little assistant, weren't you?
You help with the experiments.
Some but I don't know everything.
But you're gonna take
your daddy's notebooks
and make as much of that
fear juice as I say.
And so you don't get lonely?
The boy is here.
I brought your friend.
No.
No, make it stop!
No, you don't understand! Stop.
No, you don't understand!
Good morning,
ladies and gentlemen.
May I have your attention, please.
Hey, what the...
All the money now!
- Give it to me. All of that.
- Yes, sir, yes.
Hey, you have a license?
Oh, here.
Look at me.
Fiery demons.
It was fiery demons. Demons.
Demons, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, we'll catch him.
Get him out of here. Go, go, go.
Fiery demons.
Hey.
Did Penguin issue a license for this?
Why are you asking me?
Best of my knowledge, no.
And why do something so public?
Unless you're trying
to send Penguin a message.
I hope the message was,
"Please send Victor Zsasz
down here to kill me"
because that's exactly
what's gonna happen.
- Not if I find him first.
- Hey.
You ask me to stop busting
crooks with licenses.
This gang didn't have a license.
And you're gonna find him
before Zsasz
just to prove the G.C.P.D.
still matters?
That's not thumb in your nose
at Penguin?
- Fire me.
- Hey, don't tempt me.
You got a lead?
The victims, the way they're acting
their terror reminds me
of Crane's formula.
You think someone's using
the fear juice?
It ain't him. He's dead, remember?
Not that that matters much
in this town anymore.
He's dead.
His son isn't.
Jonathan Crane's condition
is fragile.
I'm afraid he can't see anyone
certainly not the two men
who killed his father.
Yes, so how many loonies
you got in this joint?
436 total.
We mustn't call them loonies.
Of course not.
How about staff
that had access to Crane?
Any of them not show up for work?
All present and accounted for.
- You don't wanna check?
- We don't need to.
See, that's impressive
because I ran a precinct
and if half my cops didn't show up,
I'd be none the wiser.
It's true. He wouldn't.
Clearly, we have different
professional standards.
Jonathan Crane's father
created a toxin
that makes people see
their greatest fear.
This morning it was used
to rob a bank.
How is that my problem?
Let me explain it to you.
See, whoever rob the bank
they challenge Penguin.
And all we have to do
is tell Penguin that you're involved
and he'll send Victor Zsasz
down here to talk to you.
Jim, how would you describe Victor?
Victor Zsasz...
...a homicidal maniac and sadist.
A homicidal maniac and sadist
to the highest professional
standards.
So, you can talk with us
here and now,
or you can talk to Victor.
They threatened me.
I had no choice.
We want a name, putz.
I knew it ring a bell.
Grady Harris run a crew
a few years back
and his cousin murdered
a couple of cowboys
from the sticks.
Grady!
G.C.P.D.
G.C.P.D.!
Well, well, look at what we got here.
What's wrong with you, pigs
harassing honest fellas like us
when there's real criminals
out there?
You robbed a bank in broad daylight.
That don't make you a criminal?
I'm an outlaw.
Outlaws have a code.
Criminals, they'll take everything.
They'll take a man's livelihood
like the Penguin.
And his licenses.
But we're gonna show him, you'll see.
Penguin wouldn't give you a license
if you beg him until the cows
came home, you stupid hick.
You'll lucky I'm not the Penguin.
We'll gut you right here.
We're better than them.
Take care, pigs.
They see him anyway.
Hey, check it out.
- Are you lost?
- See.
We've got a company.
She all by herself?
Just let me go, okay?
Not a chance.
Don't say I didn't warn you.
Don't turn your back on a guy
unless you're sure he's down.
Otherwise, not bad.
Does this mean we can get pizza?
I'm just saying
you steal my pepperoni again,
I'll break your fingers.
So, you're saying,
do steal your pepperoni again?
I come in peace.
You, ladies,
were not easy to track down.
Then again,
I can see why you don't advertise.
Didn't you use to be rich?
That was before your boss
stole my club.
Well, you murdered his mum,
and tried to kill him.
So...
...call it even?
There a reason you're here?
Know about these?
The boss can have you operating
on your own.
Now, we can just kill you.
But he figures it's time
to let bygones be bygones.
How big of him.
Tomorrow night's the opening
of his club.
Come by, kiss the ring
get your license.
Is that pepperoni?
Goes without saying,
this is one of those...
...or else, kind of deals.
Later.
We gotta find a new place.
Why? We join Penguin,
we can at least get work.
I came to you
because I wanted to move up
and look around.
We're barely making it.
I'm not working for him.
Now, pack.
Detective Gordon.
Bruce.
I didn't hear you.
What happened?
Nothing.
Harvey and I were tracking a gang.
We let ourselves get surprised.
What brings you down here?
I found this when I was in the city.
Wasn't sure what to do with it.
One of Penguin's licenses.
Apparently, crime is legal now
and you're going along with that?
Not really.
There's a number on the license.
I was thinking, Penguin must have
some sort of master list.
Connecting the crime and the criminal
to the license issue.
Just like that we'll tell you not
only who committed that crime
or crimes that haven't
even happened yet.
Unfortunately, the judges are going
along with the licenses
and trying to track down
who in Penguin's organization
keeps the list.
We've set off too many alarms.
I see.
But you haven't given up.
You just said you were out
tracking gang.
It's different.
This gang isn't licensed
but Penguin will come after them
if he hasn't already.
And when he catches them
it'll be more proof that Gotham
doesn't need the G.C.P.D.
Sorry, it's been a long day.
So, why don't use Penguin
to lead you to them?
If I could figure out
how to do that, I would.
It was good to see you, Detective.
Would you come by the house
for dinner?
Yes.
I'd like that.
How about we grab a bite...
...tonight?
Exclusive, but welcoming,
we're bane and edgy.
Tonight's opening will establish
that Iceberg Lounge is Gotham's
newest place to see...
...and be seen.
And you say you acquired the clip
from Barbara Kean?
Is that a question?
It's just no one's seen her
for months and...
Now, Barbara Kean's whereabouts
are not my concern.
This wasn't Sirens Club.
It is now mine.
Mr. Cobblepot, there's a rumor
going around about criminals
being given licenses.
The rumor is you're issuing them.
Tell me, what is the crime rate
in Gotham?
We're at a historic close.
Historic close.
You know, Augustus Caesar
once presided over
the longest period
of peace and prosperity
the world has ever known.
It was called the Pax Romana.
Perhaps one day, this would
be known as the Pax Penguina.
That's not a denial.
We're here to talk about my club.
Your readers
will find this interesting.
Ivy?
That's Edward Nygma.
Turns out Ed
had a very rare brain disease.
There is only one option.
To freeze him
and wait for the cure.
In his final lucid moments...
...he begged me, "Oswald
do not hide me away.
Put me out with the people."
It was the least I could do.
Anyone tell him he was being frozen?
I have affidavits from his doctor,
if you would like to see them.
No, thanks.
Well, Jim...
I'm rather busy,
so whatever your business is...
I came to tell you you're a fraud.
A gang that has Crane's fear toxin
and they're not afraid of you.
Others will find out,
and so it begins.
You've had a nice run, Oswald.
But it's over.
Coach him.
It's so hard to admit
when you've become irrelevant.
Let me tell you what's gonna happen.
I'm going to find this gang
and I'm going to crush them.
And everyone will see
that it is Oswald Cobblepot
the Penguin, who keeps Gotham safe.
Always good to see you, old friend.
As he prepares for the opening
of the Iceberg Lounge
Oswald Cobblepot announced
that he would destroy the gang
that attacked
Gotham First National Bank yesterday.
He described them
as cowards and pond scum.
Penguin's going down tonight.
Have you finished
that new batch yet?
Yes.
Oh, can you please, can you please
get rid of that, please?
What?
You and him ain't getting along?
Please, just get rid of it!
Listen, I gotta do
some things tonight,
but I think you, guys, should spend
some time together, huh?
- Please.
- We all have our fears to face.
Please, don't. I beg.
Stop, stop, please!
Stop, please!
No!
Stop!
Let me out!
Remember how you accused me
of being a slave to my emotions?
No more.
I've banished those feelings.
And look how I have risen.
But at what cost?
I wonder which of us is frozen.
Him.
He's, like, totally frozen.
Ivy, go somewhere else.
All right!
I want two unmarked units
at street level
and another two teams
of me and Harvey
watching the entrances of the club.
The moment that gang arrives,
we move.
You heard the man.
Suit up, let's go!
- Can we count on them?
- Let's see.
You tricked Penguin
into baying the gang
to attack his club,
hoping to arrest them
before they cause mass panic,
only so you could embarrass Penguin.
So, I would say, yeah,
they are about as dependable
as any other part
of this cockamamie plan.
Thanks.
I'll get the gas masks.
Please, let me out!
Jonathan.
Let me out!
So you guys work for Penguin, huh?
It ain't like that.
- Sure.
- Come on, Gordon.
Since Penguin's been cracking down,
life's been good.
Why you gotta rock the boat?
What happens when he starts
giving out licenses for murders?
Huh? What then?
I'm wasting my breath, aren't I?
Pretty much.
All right then.
Who wants to be first?
Mr. Wayne.
Mr. Pennyworth.
- I am so glad you could make it.
- It's our pleasure.
Congratulations.
We were just admiring
your frozen mates.
Is he still alive in there?
I fear we may never know.
But you'll know
when you finally thaw him out.
When they discover a cure
for his disease.
Oh, yes. Then, of course.
I wanted to personally thank you
for everything you've done
for this city.
Thank you, Mr. Wayne.
So...
...can I ask about the licenses?
A little discretion if you would,
Master Bruce.
Everybody's talking about it, Alfred.
I just wanna know how it works.
So, does someone come to you
and say, I'm gonna rob a bank?
Now, Bruce,
if I didn't know any better
I would think that you wanted me
to implicate myself.
Anything you say stays between us.
First, let me ask.
You would be agreeable
to the idea of licensed crime?
If crime have been licensed
and controlled three years ago
my parents would still be alive.
Exactly so.
Well, between us
I have nothing to do
with the licenses directly.
I provide the guidelines
while Mr. Penn
handles all of the details.
Now, would you excuse me?
- Well done, sir.
- Thank you.
Now, we know who has the list.
The next step is...
Selina.
Where is your babysitter?
It's kind of a package deal.
Yeah, well, he's got me.
Is that good enough or not?
Actually, we're both in.
We should pat you down
for weapons.
Sure, if you wanna lose a hand.
It's worth a shot.
I'll tell the boss.
See you.
You were worried about me.
Hey, man, I've been looking
all over for you.
Oh, ouch.
I think we can forget
about backup.
I see. You talked to some
of your fellow officers.
Probably not a bad thing.
- How's that?
- Guys get to let off steam.
Resentments don't fester.
Next time, you can get punched
in the face.
This beautiful mug,
no one would dare.
Let's go.
All right, once inside, get Zsasz
and Penguin first, and then go crazy.
I still don't see Penguin.
Hello.
I'm guessing that gas
isn't faster than a bullet.
What do you think?
Jim Gordon
and his ham-fisted manipulation.
He thought he fooled me.
You wanna do them here
or downstairs?
- It'd be a little loud in here.
- Neither.
I have something special
planned for them.
What do you want, Bruce?
You knew I'd follow you.
Just like I knew
that you'd come up here.
You don't know anything about me.
I wanted to apologize
for what I said at the hospital
when you came to visit Alfred.
You were making a kind gesture.
You wanna talk to me,
come up here.
My point is I'm sorry.
Yeah.
You were a jerk.
I saw you arrived
with Tabitha Galavan.
I'm not trying to choose her
as a mentor.
Wow.
That means absolutely nothing to me.
Selina.
You... you wanna say something?
It's a lovely dress
you're wearing tonight.
Honestly, you'd say.
Why can't you just go to a cinema
like normal teenagers?
Master Bruce, we've got
a bit of situation downstairs.
What sort of situation?
Let's go.
For the past three months
I have given this city
a tranquility that's never known.
Now, I would like to ensure
that peace for the future.
In the weeks to come,
you will hear whispers
about what's happening
on the streets of Gotham.
All you need to know
is, without me, this is what you get.
Men who want to bring fear
back to our city
who promised
a return to the old days.
So tell your families,
tell your friends
it is Oswald Cobblepot
who keeps them safe
not the G.C.P.D.
- You're welcome.
- That's right.
I have my things in the car, we can
stop them in the parking garage.
Absolutely not, Master Bruce.
Alfred, Penguin is gonna take
those men out and kill them.
Undoubtedly, sir.
But as you said before,
you can make a difference.
There is time for masks,
and there is a time for Bruce Wayne.
Do you know what's going
to be done to you?
Wait!
I want to know what
you're gonna do with those men.
You need not concern yourself
with that.
Are those men gonna be
turned over to the police?
Earlier tonight, you thanked me
for making this city safer.
Now, how do you think that happens?
I do the dirty work no one else will.
I understand.
But I'm asking you.
Turn those men over to the police.
You're young.
You have a good heart.
No.
Enjoy your party, Penguin.
Little twerp.
What's wrong? You scared?
Hey.
You're under arrest.
By order of the Gotham City
Police Department.
Cuff him.
Help me!
Help me! Help me!
Penguin ain't gonna be too happy.
Screw him.
I'm just worried about
finding Jonathan Crane.
If he's out there, with access
to his father's formula...
Relax. We'll find him.
Wouldn't expect too much help
from these parts though.
There's good cops out there.
They just need reminding.
You have a list
of all the licenses you've given.
- I want it.
- I...
I can't.
Penguin, he'll...
- What about the alarm?
- Forget it.
You got a license, remember?
Hey, I found it. I got it. I got it.
Everybody out. Let's go. Come on.
Move.
Oh, no.
What the...
G.C.P.D.!
Gotham Police, you're under arrest.
Crane, we gotta make more
of that fear gas.
We gotta get Merton out of jail.
Crane!
Crane?
Jonathan Crane isn't here
anymore.
It's just the Scarecrow.